OOH! CAREFUL, HOMER!
噢！小心点，霍默！
THERE'S NO TIME TO BE CAREFUL. WE'RE LATE.
没时间小心了！我们迟到了！
♪ O LITTLE TOWN OF BETHLEHEM ♪
♪ 哦，伯利恒小镇 ♪
♪ HOW STILL WE SEE THEE LIE ♪
♪ 多么宁静，你安然躺卧 ♪
SORRY. EXCUSE ME. PARDON ME.
抱歉，借过一下，不好意思。
SORRY. EXCUSE ME.
HEY, NORMAN, HOW'S IT GOIN'?
抱歉，借过一下。
嘿，诺曼，最近怎么样？
SO YOU GOT DRAGGED DOWN HERE TOO, HUH?
你也被抓来这儿啦，嗯？
HOW YOU DOIN', FRED?
SORRY. EXCUSE ME.
弗雷德，你好啊？
抱歉，借过一下。
- YEAH. 'SCUSE ME. OH!
-
- 嗯，不好意思！噢！
PARDON MY GALOSHES.
请原谅我的雨靴。
♪ ARE MET IN THEE TONIGHT ♪
♪ 今夜齐聚你城中 ♪
WASN'T THAT WONDERFUL?
刚才的表演太棒了，对吧？
AND NOW "SANTAS OF MANY LANDS,"
AS PRESENTED BY THE ENTIRE SECOND GRADE CLASS.
接下来是《各国的圣诞老人》，
由二年级全体同学倾情呈现。
OH! LISA'S CLASS.
哦！丽莎的班级！
Frohliche Weihnachten.
*Frohliche Weihnachten.*
THAT'S GERMAN FOR "MERRY CHRISTMAS."
这是德语，意思是“圣诞快乐”。
IN GERMANY, SANTA'S SERVANT RUPRECHT GIVES PRESENTS TO GOOD CHILDREN...
在德国，圣诞老人的仆人“鲁普雷希特”会给好孩子送礼物……
AND WHIPPING RODS TO THE PARENTS OF BAD ONES.
而坏孩子的父母，会收到一根鞭子。
MERRY Kurisumasu.
圣诞快乐（*Kurisumasu*）！
I AM HOTSEIOSHA, A JAPANESE PRIEST WHO ACTS LIKE SANTA CLAUS.
我是霍特赛欧沙，一位扮演圣诞老人的日本神父。
I HAVE EYES IN THE BACK OF MY HEAD...
我后脑勺也长着眼睛……
SO CHILDREN BETTER BEHAVE WHEN I'M NEARBY.
所以孩子们在我附近时，最好乖乖听话。
NOW PRESENTING LISA SIMPSON...
现在有请丽莎·辛普森……
AS TAWANGA, THE SANTA CLAUS OF THE SOUTH SEAS.
饰演南太平洋的圣诞老人——塔旺加。
OOH, IT'S LISA! THAT'S OURS.
噢，是丽莎！那是咱家的！
AH, THE FOURTH GRADE WILL NOW FAVOR US WITH A MELODY--
啊，四年级同学将为我们献上一段旋律——
UH, MEDLEY OF HOLIDAY "FLAVORITES."
呃，是一组节日“经典”串烧。
♪ DASHING THROUGH THE SNOW ♪
♪ 驾着雪橇飞奔 ♪
♪ IN A ONE-HORSE OPEN SLEIGH ♪
♪ 单马拉着敞篷雪橇 ♪
♪ O'ER THE FIELDS WE GO ♪
♪ 穿越田野飞驰 ♪
♪ LAUGHING ALL THE WAY HA HA HA ♪
♪ 一路欢笑哈哈 ♪
♪ BELLS ON BOBTAIL RING ♪
♪ 铃儿叮当响 ♪
♪ ISN'T BART SWEET, HOMER? ♪
♪ 巴特真可爱，是不是，霍默？ ♪
HE SINGS LIKE AN ANGEL.
他唱得像个天使。
♪ OH, JINGLE BELLS BATMAN SMELLS ♪
♪ 噢，铃儿响叮当，蝙蝠侠臭烘烘 ♪
♪ ROBIN LAID AN EGG ♪
♪ 罗宾下了个蛋 ♪
♪ THE BATMOBILE BROKE ITS WHEEL ♪
♪ 蝙蝠车爆了个轮胎 ♪
♪ THE JOKER GOT AWA-- ♪
♪ 小丑他逃—— ♪
♪ JINGLE BELLS JINGLE BELLS ♪
♪ 铃儿响叮当，铃儿响叮当 ♪
♪ JINGLE ALL ♪
♪ 铃儿响遍四方 ♪
THE FIFTH GRADE WILL NOW FAVOR US...
五年级同学将为我们献上……
WITH A SCENE FROM CHARLES, UH, DICKENS' A CHRISTMAS CAROL.
查尔斯……呃，狄更斯的《圣诞颂歌》片段。
HOW MANY GRADES DOES THIS SCHOOL HAVE?
这学校到底有几个年级啊？
"DEAR FRIENDS OF THE SIMPSON FAMILY,
我们辛普森家的朋友们，
"WE HAD SOME SADNESS AND SOME GLADNESS THIS YEAR.
今年我们有悲也有喜。
"FIRST, THE SADNESS. OUR LITTLE CAT SNOWBALL...
先说悲伤的事：我们的小猫雪球……
"WAS UNEXPECTEDLY RUN OVER AND WENT TO KITTY HEAVEN.
不幸被车撞了，去了猫咪天堂。
"BUT WE BOUGHT A NEW LITTLE CAT, SNOWBALL II.
“但我们又买了只新小猫，叫雪球二世。
"SO I GUESS LIFE GOES ON.
所以我想，生活还得继续。”
"SPEAKING OF LIFE GOING ON, GRANDPA IS STILL WITH US, FEISTY AS EVER.
“说到生活继续，爷爷还健在，脾气还是那么倔。
"MAGGIE IS WALKING BY HERSELF,
“玛姬已经能自己走路了，
"LISA GOT STRAIGHT A's, AND BART--
丽莎门门拿A，至于巴特嘛——
"WELL, WE LOVE BART.
“嗯，我们爱巴特。”
"THE MAGIC OF THE SEASON HAS TOUCHED US ALL.
“节日的魔力触动了我们每个人。”
MARGE, HAVEN'T YOU FINISHED THAT STUPID LETTER YET?
玛姬，那封蠢信你还没写完吗？
- "HOMER SENDS HIS LOVE. HAPPY HOLIDAYS."
- MARGE!
- “霍默送上他的爱，祝大家节日快乐。”
- 玛姬！
- "THE SIMPSONS."
- MARGE, WHERE'S THE EXTENSION CORD?
- “辛普森一家。”
- 玛姬，延长线在哪儿？
FOR HEAVEN'S SAKE, HOMER. IT'S IN THE UTILITY DRAWER.
天哪，霍默，就在工具抽屉里！
SORRY. I'M JUST A BIG KID.
抱歉，我只是个长不大的孩子。
AND I LOVE CHRISTMAS SO MUCH.
我实在太爱圣诞节了。
D'OH!
呃啊！
ALL RIGHT, CHILDREN, LET ME HAVE THOSE LETTERS.
好了，孩子们，把你们的信给我吧。
I'LL SEND THEM TO SANTA'S WORKSHOP AT THE NORTH POLE.
我会寄到北极的圣诞老人工作室。
OH, PLEASE. THERE'S ONLY ONE FAT GUY THAT BRINGS US PRESENTS,
噢，拜托，给我们送礼物的胖子可只有一个，
AND HIS NAME AIN'T SANTA.
而且他可不叫圣诞老人。
UH-- A PONY?
呃……一匹小马？
OH, LISA, YOU'VE ASKED FOR THAT FOR THE LAST THREE YEARS,
哦，丽莎，你都连续三年要小马了，
AND I KEEP TELLING YOU SANTA CAN'T FIT A PONY INTO HIS SLEIGH.
我一直在告诉你，圣诞老人的雪橇装不下小马。
CAN'T YOU TAKE A HINT?
你就不能领会一下吗？
BUT I REALLY WANT A PONY,
但我真的很想要一匹小马，
AND I'VE BEEN REALLY, REALLY GOOD THIS YEAR. OH, DEAR.
而且我今年真的、真的非常乖。噢，亲爱的。
MAYBE BART IS A LITTLE MORE REALISTIC.
也许巴特的愿望更现实一点。
- A TATTOO?
- A WHAT?
- 一个纹身？
- 什么？
YEAH! THEY'RE COOL, AND THEY LAST THE REST OF YOUR LIFE.
对啊！很酷，而且能陪你一辈子。
YOU WILL NOT BE GETTING A TATTOO FOR CHRISTMAS.
你圣诞节别想拿到纹身。
YEAH. IF YOU WANT ONE, YOU'LL HAVE TO PAY FOR IT OUT OF YOUR OWN ALLOWANCE.
没错。你要是真想要，得用自己的零花钱付。
- ALL RIGHT!
- HOMER!
- 行吧！
- 霍默！
"YELLO."
“喂。”
MARGE, PLEASE. WHO'S THIS?
玛姬，拜托。谁啊？
MAY I PLEASE SPEAK TO MARGE?
我可以跟玛姬说话吗？
THIS IS HER SISTER, ISN'T IT? IS MARGE THERE?
这是她姐姐吧？玛姬在吗？
WHO SHALL I SAY IS CALLING? MARGE, PLEASE.
请问您是哪位？玛姬，快接电话。
IT'S YOUR SISTER. OH!
是你姐姐。噢！
HELLO. HELLO, MARGE. IT'S PATTY.
喂？喂，玛姬，我是帕蒂。
SELMA AND I COULDN'T BE MORE EXCITED ABOUT SEEING OUR BABY SISTER FOR CHRISTMAS EVE.
塞尔玛和我都迫不及待想在圣诞夜见到我们的小妹妹。
WELL, HOMER AND I ARE LOOKING FORWARD TO YOUR VISIT TOO.
嗯，我和霍默也很期待你们来访。
SOMEHOW I DOUBT THAT HOMER IS EXCITED.
我可不信霍默会高兴。
OF ALL THE MEN YOU COULD'VE MARRIED,
在你能嫁的所有男人里，
I DON'T KNOW WHY YOU PICKED ONE WHO'S ALWAYS SO RUDE TO US.
真不明白你为啥选了个老对我们这么无礼的家伙。
- GOOD ONE, DAD.
-
- 干得漂亮，老爸。
OKAY, KIDS, PREPARE TO BE DAZZLED.
好了孩子们，准备好大吃一惊吧。
MARGE, TURN ON THE JUICE!
玛姬，通电吧！
WHAT DO YOU THINK, KIDS?
孩子们，你们觉得怎么样？
NICE TRY, DAD.
老爸，挺努力的。
JUST HOLD YOUR HORSES, SON. HEY, SIMPSON!
儿子，别急。嘿，辛普森！
WHAT IS IT, FLANDERS? DO YOU THINK THIS LOOKS OKAY?
怎么了，弗兰德斯？你觉得我这个看起来还行吗？
HO HO HO. HO HO HO.
呵呵呵。呵呵呵。
OH! OH, NEATO!
噢！哇，太酷了！
IT'S TOO BRIGHT.
太亮了。
I OUGHTA-- FLANDERS. WHAT A BIG SHOW-OFF.
我该——弗兰德斯。真是个爱显摆的家伙。
- KIDS, YOU WANNA GO CHRISTMAS SHOPPING?
- I DO!
- 孩子们，想去买圣诞礼物吗？
- 我想去！
- ALL RIGHT! THE MALL!
- GO GET YOUR MONEY.
- 好嘞！去商场！
- 去拿你们的钱。
TELL US, MARGE. WHERE HAVE YOU BEEN HIDING THE CHRISTMAS MONEY?
告诉我们，玛姬，你把圣诞钱藏哪儿了？
OH, I HAVE MY SECRETS.
哦，我自有我的秘密。
TURN AROUND.
转过去。
- YOU CAN LOOK NOW.
- OOH! BIG JAR THIS YEAR.
- 现在可以看了。
- 哇！今年存钱罐好大啊。
OH, BART, THAT'S SO SWEET.
哦，巴特，你真是太贴心了。
IT'S THE BEST PRESENT A MOTHER COULD GET,
这是妈妈能收到的最好的礼物，
AND IT MAKES YOU LOOK SO DANGEROUS.
而且让你看起来超酷。
ONE "MOTHER," PLEASE.
来一份“妈妈”，谢谢。
WAIT A MINUTE. HOW OLD ARE YOU?
等等，你多大了？
- TWENTY-ONE, SIR.
- GET IN THE CHAIR.
- 二十一岁，先生。
- 坐下吧。
MM-HMM.
嗯哼。
MM-HMM. MM-HMM.
嗯哼。嗯哼。
ATTENTION, ALL PERSONNEL, PLEASE KEEP WORKING...
各位员工请注意，请继续工作……
DURING THE FOLLOWING ANNOUNCEMENT.
在以下通知期间。
AND NOW OUR BOSS AND FRIEND MR. BURNS.
现在有请我们的老板兼朋友——伯恩斯先生。
HELLO. I'M PROUD TO ANNOUNCE...
大家好。我很自豪地宣布……
THAT WE'VE BEEN ABLE TO INCREASE SAFETY HERE AT THE PLANT...
我们成功提高了工厂的安全水平……
WITHOUT INCREASING THE COST TO THE CONSUMER...
而没有增加消费者的成本……
OR AFFECTING MANAGEMENT PAY RAISES.
也没影响管理层的加薪。
HOWEVER, FOR YOU SEMISKILLED WORKERS,
不过，对于你们这些半熟练工，
THERE WILL BE NO CHRISTMAS BONUSES.
今年没有圣诞奖金。
OH, AND ONE MORE THING.
哦，还有一件事。
MERRY CHRISTMAS!
圣诞快乐！
OH, THANK GOD FOR THE BIG JAR.
谢天谢地还有那个大存钱罐。
WHERE'S THAT BART?
巴特那小子跑哪儿去了？
BUT, MOM, I THOUGHT YOU'D LIKE IT.
可是妈妈，我以为你会喜欢的。
YES, MRS. SIMPSON, WE CAN REMOVE YOUR SON'S TATTOO.
是的，辛普森太太，我们可以去掉你儿子的纹身。
IT'S A SIMPLE ROUTINE INVOLVING LASERS.
这是个简单的激光手术。
- COOL!
- HOWEVER, IT IS RATHER EXPENSIVE,
- 酷！
- 不过费用相当高，
AND WE MUST INSIST ON A CASH PAYMENT UP FRONT.
而且必须先付现金。
CASH? MM-HMM.
现金？嗯哼。
THANK GOD FOR HOMER'S CHRISTMAS BONUS.
感谢上帝还有霍默的圣诞奖金。
¡Ay, caramba! NOW, WHATEVER YOU DO, BOY, DON'T SQUIRM.
哎呀！孩子，不管你做什么，千万别乱动。
YOU DON'T WANNA GET THIS SUCKER NEAR YOUR EYE OR YOUR GROIN.
你可不想让这玩意儿碰到你的眼睛或下体。
OW! QUIT IT.
哎哟！别动！
OW! QUIT IT. HEY, WHAT'S WITH THIS?
哎哟！别动！嘿，这是怎么回事？
OW! QUIT IT! USED TO BE A REAL BOSS TATTOO.
哎哟！别动！以前可是个超酷的纹身。
BUT MOM HAD TO SPEND ALL THE CHRISTMAS MONEY HAVING IT SURGICALLY REMOVED.
但妈妈不得不花光所有圣诞钱做手术去掉它。
HUH?
嗯？
IT'S TRUE!
是真的！
THE JAR IS EMPTY! OH, MY GOD!
存钱罐空了！天啊！
WE'RE RUINED. CHRISTMAS IS CANCELED.
我们完蛋了。圣诞节取消了。
NO PRESENTS FOR ANYONE!
谁也别想有礼物了！
DON'T WORRY, HOMER. WE'LL JUST HAVE TO STRETCH YOUR CHRISTMAS BONUS...
别担心，霍默。我们只能把你的圣诞奖金再省着点花了……
EVEN FURTHER THIS YEAR.
今年得省得更厉害了。
- HOMER?
- OH, YEAH. MY CHRISTMAS BONUS.
- 霍默？
- 噢，对啊。我的圣诞奖金。
HOW SILLY OF ME.
我可真傻。
THIS'LL BE THE BEST CHRISTMAS YET.
这会是有史以来最棒的圣诞节。
THE BEST ANY FAMILY NEVER HAD.
也是任何家庭从未拥有过的“最棒”。
HO HO HO.
呵呵呵。
HMM. I GET THE FEELING THERE'S SOMETHING YOU HAVEN'T TOLD ME, HOMER.
嗯……我觉得你有事瞒着我，霍默。
- HUH? OH. I LOVE YOU, MARGE.
- YOU TELL ME THAT ALL THE TIME.
- 啊？哦。我爱你，玛姬。
- 你老这么说。
OH, GOOD, BECAUSE I DO LOVE YOU.
那就好，因为我确实爱你。
I DON'T DESERVE YOU AS MUCH AS A GUY WITH A FAT WALLET...
我配不上你，不像那些钱包鼓鼓的男人……
AND A CREDIT CARD THAT WON'T SET OFF THAT HORRIBLE BEEPING.
还有信用卡不会发出那种可怕“嘀嘀”声的人。
I THINK IT DOES HAVE SOMETHING TO DO WITH YOUR CHRISTMAS BONUS.
我觉得这跟你圣诞奖金有关。
I KEEP ASKING FOR IT, BUT--
我一直问你要，但——
MARGE, UM, LET ME BE HONEST WITH YOU.
玛姬，嗯……让我对你坦白吧。
YES? WELL, I WOULD--
好啊？那我——
I-- I WANNA DO THE CHRISTMAS SHOPPING THIS YEAR.
我……我想今年负责买圣诞礼物。
UH, SURE, OKAY.
呃，行吧。
MARGE, MARGE. HMM. LET'S SEE.
玛姬，玛姬。嗯……看看。
OOH, LOOK!
噢，看！
PANTYHOSE. PRACTICAL AND ALLURING.
连裤袜。实用又迷人。
A SIX-PACK. OH! ONLY 4.99.
六罐装啤酒。噢！才4.99。
OOH! PADS OF PAPER.
噢！一叠纸。
I BET BART CAN THINK OF A MILLION THINGS TO DO WITH THESE.
我打赌巴特能想出一百万种玩法。
THAT JUST LEAVES LITTLE MAGGIE. OH, LOOK!
那就只剩小玛姬了。噢，看！
A LITTLE SQUEAK TOY.
一个小 squeak 玩具。
IT SAYS IT'S FOR DOGS, BUT SHE CAN'T READ.
上面写着是给狗的，但她又不识字。
OW! OH, SIMPSON, IT'S YOU.
哎哟！哦，辛普森，是你啊。
HELLO, FLANDERS. OH, MY! WHAT A LITTLE MESS WE'VE GOT HERE.
你好，弗兰德斯。天哪！我们这儿可真乱啊。
WELL, WHICH ONES ARE YOURS AND WHICH ONES ARE MINE?
那哪些是你的，哪些是我的？
WELL, LET'S SEE. OH, THIS ONE'S MINE. THIS ONE'S MINE.
嗯，让我看看。哦，这个是我的，这个也是我的。
THIS ONE'S MINE, AND THIS-- THEY'RE ALL YOURS!
这个是我的，还有这个——全都是你的！
HEY, MR. SIMPSON, YOU DROPPED YOUR PORK CHOP.
嘿，辛普森先生，你的猪排掉了。
- GIMME THAT!
- WELL, HAPPY HOLIDAYS, SIMPSON.
- 给我！
- 那祝你节日快乐，辛普森。
GEE, DAD, THIS IS GONNA BE THE BEST CHRISTMAS EVER. YOU BET.
天哪，老爸，这会是有史以来最棒的圣诞节。那当然。
WHAT'S THE MATTER, HOMER? SOMEBODY LEAVE A LUMP OF COAL IN YOUR STOCKING?
怎么了，霍默？有人往你袜子里塞煤块了？
YOU'VE BEEN SITTING THERE, SUCKING ON A BEER ALL DAY LONG.
你一整天就坐在那儿，灌啤酒。
SO? SO, IT'S CHRISTMAS.
那又怎样？今天可是圣诞节。
THANKS, MOE.
谢谢，莫。
DRINKS ALL AROUND!
大家喝一杯！
WHAT'S WITH THE CRAZY GETUP, BARN?
巴尼，你这身打扮是怎么回事？
I GOT ME A PART-TIME JOB WORKING AS A SANTA DOWN AT THE MALL.
我在商场找了份兼职，扮圣诞老人。
WOW! CAN I DO THAT?
哇！我能干这个吗？
- I DON'T KNOW.
- THEY'RE PRETTY SELECTIVE.
- 不知道。
- 他们挑得很严。
DO YOU LIKE CHILDREN?
你喜欢小孩吗？
WHAT DO YOU MEAN? ALL THE TIME? EVEN WHEN THEY'RE NUTS?
什么意思？一直喜欢？就算他们疯疯癫癫也喜欢？
- HMM.
- UH, I CERTAINLY DO.
- 嗯……
- 呃，当然喜欢。
WELCOME ABOARD, SIMPSON.
欢迎加入，辛普森。
PENDING YOUR SUCCESSFUL COMPLETION OF OUR TRAINING PROGRAM, THAT IS.
前提是你要通过我们的培训。
HO HO HO. HO HO HO.
呵呵呵。呵呵呵。
- WHAT IS IT NOW, SIMPSON?
- UH, WHEN DO WE GET PAID?
- 又怎么了，辛普森？
- 呃，我们什么时候发工资？
NOT A DIME TILL CHRISTMAS EVE! NOW, FROM THE TOP.
圣诞夜前一分钱都没有！来，从头开始。
HO HO HO. HO HO HO.
呵呵呵。呵呵呵。
UM, DASHER.
呃，猛冲。
DANCER. MM-HMM.
舞者。嗯哼。
PRANCER. MM-HMM.
欢腾。嗯哼。
NIXON.
尼克松。
COMET AND... CUPID.
彗星……还有丘比特。
DONNA DIXON? SIT DOWN, SIMPSON.
唐娜·狄克逊？坐下吧，辛普森。
AND WHAT WOULD YOU LIKE, LITTLE BOY?
小朋友，你想要什么？
YOU'RE NOT REALLY SANTA, TUBBY. WHY, YOU LITTLE EGGHEAD!
你根本不是圣诞老人，胖子！你这个小书呆子！
NO, HOMER! IF SUCH AN EMERGENCY ARISES,
不，霍默！万一遇到这种情况，
YOU JUST TELL THEM SANTA'S VERY BUSY THIS TIME OF YEAR,
你就告诉他们圣诞老人年底特别忙，
AND YOU ARE ONE OF HIS HELPERS. OH, I KNEW THAT ONE TOO!
而你是他的助手之一。哦，这个我也知道！
HOMER, WHY ARE YOU SEVEN HOURS LATE?
霍默，你为什么晚了七个小时？
NOT A WORD, MARGE. I'M HEADING STRAIGHT FOR THE TUB.
一个字也别说，玛姬。我要直接去泡澡。
BUT, HOMER, MY SISTERS ARE HERE.
可是霍默，我姐姐们来了。
DON'T YOU WANNA SAY HELLO?
你不想打个招呼吗？
DADDY! DADDY! WE'RE SO GLAD TO SEE YOU! OH, DAD, YOU'RE FINALLY HOME!
爸爸！爸爸！见到你太高兴了！哦，老爸，你终于回家了！
WHAT? WHY? OH, YEAH.
什么？为什么？哦，对了。
HELLO, PATTY. HELLO, SELMA.
你好，帕蒂。你好，塞尔玛。
HOW WAS YOUR TRIP? FINE.
路上顺利吗？还行。
- YOU BOTH LOOK WELL.
- THANK YOU.
- 你们气色都不错。
- 谢谢。
YEAH, WELL, MERRY CHRISTMAS. IT'S CHRISTMAS?
嗯，圣诞快乐。今天是圣诞节？
YOU WOULDN'T KNOW IT AROUND HERE. AND WHY IS THAT?
在这儿可看不出来。为什么？
- FOR ONE THING, THERE'S NO TREE
- WELL, I WAS JUST ON MY WAY OUT TO GET ONE!
- 首先，连棵圣诞树都没有。
- 我正要出门去买一棵呢！
CAN WE GO TOO, DAD? YEAH, CAN WE?
我们能一起去吗，老爸？能去吗？
NO!
不行！
♪ SLEIGH BELLS RING ♪
♪ 铃儿响叮当 ♪
♪ ARE YOU LISTENING ♪
♪ 你听见了吗 ♪
♪ IN THE LANE ♪
♪ 在小路上 ♪
♪ SNOW IS GLISTENING ♪
♪ 雪在闪耀 ♪
♪ A BEAUTIFUL SIGHT ♪
♪ 多美的景色 ♪
♪ WE'RE HAPPY TONIGHT ♪
♪ 今晚我们真开心 ♪
♪ WALKING IN A WINTER WONDERLAND ♪
♪ 漫步在冬日仙境 ♪
HEY, YOU! WHAT DO YOU THINK YOU'RE DOIN'?
喂！你以为你在干什么？
UH-OH. HEY! HEY!
糟了。嘿！嘿！
COME BACK HERE!
给我回来！
SO WHAT DO YOU THINK, KIDS? BEAUTY, ISN'T IT?
孩子们，你们觉得怎么样？漂亮吧？
WOW! YAY, DAD! WAY TO GO, DAD!
哇！耶，老爸！干得漂亮，老爸！
- WHY IS THERE A BIRDHOUSE IN IT?
- UH, THAT'S AN ORNAMENT.
- 为什么上面有个鸟屋？
- 呃，那是装饰品。
DO I SMELL GUNPOWDER?
我闻到火药味了？
AND THEN I WANT SOME ROBOTOIDS.
我还想要些机器人。
AND THEN I WANT A GOOP MONSTER.
还要一个黏液怪兽。
AND THEN I WANT A GREAT BIG, GIANT--
还要一个超级大——
AW, SON, YOU DON'T NEED ALL THAT JUNK.
哎呀，儿子，你不需要那些破烂。
I'M SURE YOU'VE ALREADY GOT SOMETHING MUCH MORE IMPORTANT--
我相信你已经有更重要的东西了——
A DECENT HOME AND A LOVING FATHER WHO WOULD DO ANYTHING FOR YOU.
一个像样的家，和一个愿意为你做任何事的慈爱父亲。
HEY, I COULDN'T AFFORD LUNCH. GIVE ME A BITE OF THAT DONUT.
嘿，我午饭都吃不起。分我一口甜甜圈。
GET A LOAD OF THAT QUOTE-UNQUOTE SANTA.
瞧瞧那个所谓的“圣诞老人”。
I CAN'T BELIEVE THOSE KIDS ARE FALLING FOR IT.
真不敢相信那些小孩还信这个。
HEY, MILHOUSE, I DARE YOU TO SIT ON HIS LAP.
嘿，米尔豪斯，我赌你不敢坐他腿上。
- OH, YEAH? WELL, I DARE YOU TO YANK HIS BEARD OFF.
- AH, TOUCHE.
- 哦，是吗？那我赌你敢扯掉他的胡子。
- 哎呀，服了。
I HOPE YOU FEEL BETTER, SANTA.
希望你好点，圣诞老人。
OH, I WILL WHEN MRS. CLAUS' SISTERS GET OUTTA TOWN.
等克劳斯太太的姐姐们离开镇子，我就好了。
THANKS FOR LISTENIN', KID.
谢谢你听我说，孩子。
HEY, SANTA, WHAT'S SHAKIN', MAN?
嘿，圣诞老人，最近咋样，伙计？
WHAT'S YOUR NAME, BART... NER? UH, LITTLE PARTNER?
你叫什么名字，巴特……书呆子？呃，小朋友？
- I'M BART SIMPSON. WHO THE HELL ARE YOU?
- I'M JOLLY OLD ST. NICK.
- 我是巴特·辛普森。你谁啊？
- 我是快乐的老圣尼克。
OH, YEAH? WE'LL JUST SEE ABOUT THAT.
哦，是吗？咱们走着瞧。
D'OH!
呃啊！
HOMER! I WANT A WORD WITH YOU IN SANTA'S WORKSHOP.
霍默！我要在圣诞老人小屋里跟你谈谈。
- COVER FOR ME, ELFIE.
- DON'T KILL ME, DAD. I DIDN'T KNOW IT WAS YOU.
- 掩护我一下，小精灵。
- 别杀我，老爸。我不知道是你。
NOBODY KNOWS. IT'S A SECRET.
没人知道。这是个秘密。
I DIDN'T GET MY BONUS THIS YEAR.
我今年没拿到奖金。
BUT TO KEEP THE FAMILY FROM MISSING OUT ON CHRISTMAS,
但为了不让家人错过圣诞节，
I'D DO ANYTHING. I'LL SAY, DAD.
我什么都愿意做。老爸，你真行。
YOU MUST REALLY LOVE US TO SINK SO LOW.
你一定非常爱我们，才会沦落到这种地步。
NOW, LET'S NOT GET MUSHY, SON.
别煽情了，儿子。
I STILL HAVE A JOB TO DO.
我还有工作要做。
HEY, LITTLE ONES. SANTA'S BACK.
嘿，小朋友们，圣诞老人回来了。
HO HO-- D'OH!
呵呵——呃啊！
DAMN IT TO--
该死的——
AH, SON, ONE DAY YOU'RE GONNA KNOW...
啊，儿子，总有一天你会明白……
THE SATISFACTION OF PAYDAY.
发薪日的满足感。
RECEIVING A BIG FAT CHECK FOR A JOB WELL DONE.
因为干得好，拿到一张厚厚的大支票。
SIMPSON, HOMER? HERE YA GO.
辛普森，霍默？给你。
COME ON, SON. LET'S GO CASH THIS BABY AND GET PRESENTS FOR--
走吧，儿子。咱们去兑现这张支票，给大伙买礼物——
THIRTEEN BUCKS? HEY, WAIT A MINUTE.
十三块钱？等等。
THAT'S RIGHT. $120 GROSS.
没错。税前120块。
LESS SOCIAL SECURITY, LESS UNEMPLOYMENT INSURANCE,
扣掉社保，扣掉失业保险，
- LESS SANTA TRAINING...
- SANTA TRAINING?
- 再扣圣诞老人培训费……
- 圣诞老人培训费？
LESS COSTUME PURCHASE, LESS BEARD RENTAL, LESS CHRISTMAS CLUB.
再扣服装费、胡子租金、圣诞储蓄会费。
- BUT-- BUT--
- SEE YA NEXT YEAR.
- 可是——可是——
- 明年见。
OHH! COME ON, DAD. LET'S GO HOME.
唉！走吧，老爸，咱们回家。
THIRTEEN BUCKS?
十三块钱？
YOU CAN'T GET ANYTHING FOR 13 BUCKS.
十三块钱什么都买不了。
ALL RIGHT! THIRTEEN BIG ONES!
好吧！十三张大钞！
SPRINGFIELD DOWNS, HERE I COME!
斯普林菲尔德赛狗场，我来了！
- WHAT?
- YOU HEARD ME.
- 什么？
- 你听见了。
I'M GOIN' TO THE DOG TRACK.
我要去赛狗场。
I GOT A HOT LITTLE PUPPY IN THE FOURTH RACE.
第四场比赛我押了匹热门小狗。
WANNA COME? SORRY, BARNEY.
要一起来吗？抱歉，巴尼。
I MAY BE A TOTAL WASHOUT AS A FATHER, BUT I'M NOT GONNA TAKE MY KID...
我可能是个彻底失败的父亲，但我不会带孩子……
TO A SLEAZY DOG TRACK ON CHRISTMAS EVE.
在圣诞夜去那种下流的赛狗场。
COME ON, SIMPSON. THE DOG'S NAME IS WHIRLWIND.
来吧，辛普森。那狗叫旋风。
TEN-TO-ONE SHOT. MONEY IN THE BANK.
十赔一。稳赚不赔。
- UH-UH.
- AH, COME ON, DAD.
- 呃，不行。
- 拜托啦，老爸。
THIS CAN BE THE MIRACLE THAT SAVES THE SIMPSONS' CHRISTMAS.
这会是拯救辛普森家圣诞节的奇迹。
IF TV HAS TAUGHT ME ANYTHING,
如果电视教会了我什么，
IT'S THAT MIRACLES ALWAYS HAPPEN TO POOR KIDS AT CHRISTMAS.
那就是圣诞节奇迹总会降临在穷孩子身上。
IT HAPPENED TO TINY TIM, IT HAPPENED TO CHARLIE BROWN, IT HAPPENED TO THE SMURFS,
小提姆经历过，查理·布朗经历过，蓝精灵也经历过，
AND IT'S GONNA HAPPEN TO US.
这次轮到我们了。
WELL, OKAY, LET'S GO. WHO'S TINY TIM?
好吧，走吧。小提姆是谁？
HEY, MOLDY, DO YOU THINK SANTA WILL BE ABLE TO FIND...
嘿，霉霉，你觉得圣诞老人能在……
ELF COUNTY UNDER ALL THIS SNOW?
这么大的雪下找到精灵县吗？
I DOUBT IT, BUBBLES. WE'LL BE SAD LITTLE ELVES THIS CHRISTMAS.
恐怕不能，泡泡。今年我们要当伤心的小精灵了。
OH, NO! OH, BROTHER.
哦，不！天哪。
WHERE'S YOUR HUSBAND? YEAH. IT'S GETTING LATE.
你丈夫呢？是啊，天都晚了。
SAID HE WENT CAROLING WITH BART.
说他和巴特去唱圣诞颂歌了。
♪ WE'RE IN THE MONEY WE'RE IN THE MONEY ♪
♪ 我们发财啦，我们发财啦 ♪
♪ WE GOT A LOT OF WHAT IT TAKES TO GET ALONG ♪
♪ 我们拥有了过日子所需的一切 ♪
I CAN'T BELIEVE I'M DOING THIS.
我不敢相信自己在干这事。
CAN WE OPEN OUR PRESENTS NOW, DAD?
我们现在能拆礼物了吗，老爸？
YOU KNOW THE TRADITION, SON. NOT TILL THE EIGHTH RACE.
你知道规矩，儿子。要等到第八场比赛。
HEY, BARNEY, WHICH ONE IS WHIRLWIND?
嘿，巴尼，哪只是旋风？
NUMBER SIX. THAT'S OUR LUCKY DOG RIGHT OVER THERE.
六号。就是那边那只幸运狗。
HE'S WON HIS LAST FIVE RACES.
它已经连赢五场了。
WHAT? THAT SCRAWNY LITTLE BAG OF BONES?
什么？那只瘦骨嶙峋的小可怜？
COME ON, DAD. THEY'RE ALL SCRAWNY LITTLE BAGS OF BONES.
拜托，老爸。它们都是瘦骨嶙峋的小可怜。
YEAH, YOU'RE RIGHT.
是啊，你说得对。
I GUESS WHIRLWIND IS OUR ONLY HOPE FOR A MERRY CHRISTMAS.
看来旋风是我们圣诞快乐的唯一希望了。
ATTENTION, RACING FANS, WE HAVE A LATE SCRATCH...
各位赛狗迷请注意，临时有退赛……
IN THE FOURTH RACE.
第四场比赛。
NUMBER 8, SIR GALAHAD WILL BE REPLACED BY SANTA'S LITTLE HELPER.
八号，高文爵士将由“圣诞小帮手”顶替。
ONCE AGAIN, SIR GALAHAD HAS BEEN REPLACED BY SANTA'S LITTLE HELPER.
再次通知：高文爵士由“圣诞小帮手”顶替。
BART, DID YOU HEAR THAT?
巴特，你听见了吗？
WHAT A NAME! SANTA'S LITTLE HELPER!
多棒的名字！“圣诞小帮手”！
IT'S A SIGN! IT'S AN OMEN! IT'S A COINCIDENCE, DAD.
这是预兆！是征兆！只是巧合，老爸。
- WHAT ARE THE ODDS ON SANTA'S LITTLE HELPER?
- NINETY-NINE TO ONE.
- “圣诞小帮手”的赔率是多少？
- 九十九比一。
WOW! NINETY-NINE TIMES THIRTEEN EQUALS... MERRY CHRISTMAS!
哇！99乘以13等于……圣诞快乐！
I GOT A BAD FEELING ABOUT THIS.
我有种不祥的预感。
DON'T YOU BELIEVE IN ME, SON? UH--
你不相信我吗，儿子？呃——
COME ON, BOY. SOMETIMES YOUR FAITH IS ALL THAT KEEPS ME GOING.
来吧，孩子。有时候你的信任是我坚持下去的唯一动力。
OH, GO FOR IT, DAD.
哦，放手一搏吧，老爸。
THAT'S MY BOY! EVERYTHING ON SANTA'S LITTLE HELPER.
好样的！全押“圣诞小帮手”！
THREE CHEERS FOR BRAINY!
为聪明鬼欢呼三声！
- HIP HIP HOORAY!
- YAY!
- 万岁！
- 耶！
UNADULTERATED PAP.
纯粹的废话。
IT'S ALMOST 9:00. WHERE'S HOMER ANYWAY?
快九点了。霍默到底去哪儿了？
IT'S SO TYPICAL OF THE BIG DOOFUS TO SPOIL IT ALL.
那个大笨蛋总是把事情搞砸。
- WHAT, AUNT PATTY?
- OH, NOTHING, DEAR.
- 怎么了，帕蒂阿姨？
- 哦，没什么，亲爱的。
I'M JUST TRASHING YOUR FATHER.
我只是在说你爸爸的坏话。
WELL, I WISH YOU WOULDN'T...
我希望你别这样……
BECAUSE ASIDE FROM THE FACT THAT HE HAS THE SAME FRAILTIES AS ALL HUMAN BEINGS,
因为除了他和所有凡人一样有缺点之外，
HE'S THE ONLY FATHER I HAVE.
他是我唯一的父亲。
THEREFORE, HE IS MY MODEL OF MANHOOD,
因此，他是我男子气概的榜样，
AND MY ESTIMATION OF HIM WILL GOVERN THE PROSPECTS OF MY ADULT RELATIONSHIPS.
我对他的评价将决定我成年后人际关系的前景。
SO I HOPE YOU BEAR IN MIND THAT ANY KNOCK AT HIM IS A KNOCK AT ME,
所以希望你记住，任何对他的贬低都是对我的贬低，
AND I'M FAR TOO YOUNG TO DEFEND MYSELF AGAINST SUCH ONSLAUGHTS.
而我年纪太小，无力抵御这种攻击。
MM-HMM. GO WATCH YOUR CARTOON SHOW, DEAR.
嗯哼。去看你的动画片吧，亲爱的。
COME ON, BART.
来吧，巴特。
KISS THE TICKET FOR GOOD LUCK, NOT THAT WE NEED IT.
亲一下彩票求好运，虽然我们不需要。
HERE COMES SCREWY THE MECHANICAL RABBIT.
机械兔子“歪歪”上场了。
AND THEY'RE OFF!
比赛开始！
COME ON, SANTA'S LITTLE HELPER! COME ON, DOG! GO, MAN, GO!
加油，“圣诞小帮手”！加油，狗狗！冲啊，伙计，冲啊！
IT'S WHIRLWIND IN THE LANE, AND COMING UP ON THE LEFT IS QUADRUPED,
旋风领先，左边追上来的是四足，
FOLLOWED BY DOG O'WAR AND FIDO.
后面是战狗和菲多。
GO! COME ON, BOY! GO, SANTA'S LITTLE HELPER! COME ON, GET THAT RABBIT!
冲！加油，孩子！冲啊，“圣诞小帮手”！快去抓兔子！
DOG O'WAR COMING UP FAST ON THE OUTSIDE.
战狗从外道快速追上！
COME ON, SANTA'S LITTLE HELPER! COME ON, DOG! GO, MAN, GO!
加油，“圣诞小帮手”！加油，狗狗！冲啊，伙计，冲啊！
AND WITH A LOCK ON LAST PLACE, IT'S SANTA'S LITTLE HELPER.
稳稳垫底的是“圣诞小帮手”。
DON'T WORRY, DAD.
别担心，老爸。
MAYBE THIS IS JUST FOR SUSPENSE BEFORE THE MIRACLE HAPPENS.
也许这只是奇迹发生前的悬念。
COME ON, YOU STUPID DOG! COME ON, BOY! GO, GO!
快点，你这笨狗！加油，孩子！冲啊，冲啊！
RUN! RUN! RUN, BABY, RUN! COME ON, GET THAT RABBIT!
跑！跑！快跑，宝贝，快跑！去抓兔子啊！
- GO, GO, SANTA'S LITTLE HELPER! RUN, BABY, RUN!
- GO, GO, GO!
- 冲啊，冲啊，“圣诞小帮手”！快跑，宝贝，快跑！
- 冲啊，冲啊，冲啊！
WHIRLWIND BY A COUNTRY MILE, AND IN SECOND, CHEW MY SHOE, FOLLOWED BY DOG O'WAR.
旋风遥遥领先，第二名是“咬我鞋”，战狗紧随其后。
OH, JEEZ!
哦，天哪！
DOESN'T SEEM POSSIBLE, BUT I GUESS TV HAS BETRAYED ME.
难以置信，但看来电视骗了我。
I DON'T WANNA LEAVE TILL OUR DOG FINISHES.
我不想走，直到我们的狗跑完。
AH, FORGET IT. LET'S GO.
唉，算了。走吧。
FIND ANY WINNERS, SON? SORRY, DAD.
找到赢家了吗，儿子？抱歉，老爸。
HEY, HEY, SIMPSON! WHAT'D I TELL YOU?
嘿，辛普森！我说什么来着？
- WHIRLWIND!
- LET'S GO, DARIA.
- 旋风！
- 走吧，达莉亚。
BEAT IT! SCRAM! GET LOST!
滚开！快走！消失！
YOU CAME IN LAST FOR THE LAST TIME!
这是你最后一次垫底了！
LOOK, DAD, IT'S SANTA'S LITTLE HELPER.
看，老爸，是“圣诞小帮手”。
AND DON'T COME BACK!
别再回来了！
OH, NO, YOU DON'T! NO, NO! GET AWAY FROM ME! UH-UH!
不，你别想！不，不！离我远点！呃，不行！
OH, CAN WE KEEP HIM, DAD, PLEASE?
哦，老爸，我们可以养它吗？求你了！
BUT HE'S A LOSER! HE'S PATHETIC! HE'S--
但它是个失败者！太可怜了！它——
A SIMPSON.
一个辛普森。
HMM. MAYBE I SHOULD CALL THE POLICE.
嗯……也许我该报警。
OH, HE'LL SOBER UP. YEAH. COME STAGGERING HOME.
哦，他会醒酒的。对，会摇摇晃晃地回家。
MM-HMM. SMELLING OF CHEAP PERFUME.
嗯哼。身上还带着廉价香水味。
HOMER!
霍默！
- WHAT? WHAT THE-- WHO THE--
- LOOK, EVERYBODY,
- 什么？怎么回事——谁——
- 大家看，
I HAVE A CONFESSION TO MAKE. THIS SHOULD BE GOOD.
我有件事要坦白。这下有好戏看了。
I DIDN'T GET MY CHRISTMAS BONUS.
我没拿到圣诞奖金。
I TRIED NOT TO LET IT RUIN CHRISTMAS FOR EVERYBODY,
我不想让这事毁了大家的圣诞节，
BUT NO MATTER WHAT I DID--
但不管我怎么做——
HEY, EVERYBODY, LOOK WHAT WE GOT!
大家快看，我们得到了什么！
A DOG! ALL RIGHT, DAD!
一只狗！太棒了，老爸！
- GOD BLESS HIM.
- SO LOVE AT FIRST SIGHT IS POSSIBLE.
- 愿上帝保佑它。
- 所以一见钟情是可能的。
AND IF HE RUNS AWAY, HE'LL BE EASY TO CATCH.
而且就算它跑了，也容易抓回来。
OH, THIS IS THE BEST GIFT OF ALL, HOMER!
哦，霍默，这是最好的礼物！
IT IS? YES. SOMETHING TO SHARE OUR LOVE...
是吗？是的。一个能分享我们爱的……
AND FRIGHTEN PROWLERS.
还能吓跑小偷。
- WHAT'S HIS NAME?
- NUMBER 8--
- 它叫什么名字？
- 八号——
I MEAN, SANTA'S LITTLE HELPER.
我是说，“圣诞小帮手”。
♪ RUDOLPH THE RED-NOSED REINDEER ♪
♪ 红鼻子驯鹿鲁道夫 ♪
♪ HAD A VERY SHINY NOSE ♪
♪ 有个闪亮的红鼻子 ♪
♪ AND IF YOU EVER SAW IT ♪
♪ 如果你见过它 ♪
♪ YOU WOULD EVEN SAY IT GLOWS LIKE A LIGHT BULB!
♪ 你甚至会说它像灯泡一样发光！
BART! ♪ ALL OF THE OTHER REINDEER ♪
巴特！♪ 其他驯鹿都 ♪
♪ USED TO LAUGH AND CALL HIM NAMES ♪
♪ 笑他，给他起外号 ♪
- LIKE SHNOZZOLA!
- LISA!
- 比如“大鼻头”！
- 丽莎！
♪ THEY NEVER LET POOR RUDOLPH ♪
♪ 他们从不让可怜的鲁道夫 ♪
♪ JOIN IN ANY REINDEER GAMES LIKE STRIP POKER!
♪ 参加任何驯鹿游戏，比如脱衣扑克！
I'M WARNING YOU TWO! ♪ THEN ONE FOGGY CHRISTMAS EVE ♪
我警告你们俩！♪ 直到一个雾蒙蒙的圣诞夜 ♪
♪ SANTA CAME TO SAY ♪ TAKE IT, HOMER!
♪ 圣诞老人来到他说 ♪ 接着唱，霍默！
♪ UH, RUDOLPH GET YOUR NOSE OVER HERE ♪
♪ 呃，鲁道夫，把你的鼻子凑过来 ♪
♪ SO YOU CAN GUIDE MY SLEIGH TODAY ♪ OH, HOMER.
♪ 好让你今天为我引路 ♪ 哦，霍默。
♪ THEN ALL THE REINDEER LOVED HIM ♪
♪ 于是所有驯鹿都爱他 ♪
♪ AND THEY SHOUTED OUT WITH GLEE ♪
♪ 他们欢呼雀跃 ♪
♪ RUDOLPH THE RED-NOSED REINDEER ♪
♪ 红鼻子驯鹿鲁道夫 ♪
♪ YOU'LL GO DOWN IN HISTORY ♪
♪ 你的名字将永载史册 ♪
♪ LIKE ATTILA THE HU-- ♪ YOU LITTLE--
♪ 就像阿提拉匈—— ♪ 你这个小——
SHH.
嘘——